The question of whether it has come or not has already come and is accelerating.
到底来了还是没来的问题已经来了，并且正在加速。
This is my opening speech today at EAG.
这是我今天在 EAG 的开幕致辞。
Thank you, everyone.
谢谢大家。
I'm curious about how many of you are builders on Ethereum right now.
我很好奇现在有多少人是以太坊的开发者。
You can raise your hand.
你可以举手。
And how many of you are holders of Ethereum right now?
现在你们中有多少人是以太坊的持有者？
Okay.
好的。
Thank you for coming.
谢谢您的光临。
Please welcome Ayat and Audrey.
欢迎阿亚特和奥黛丽。
Hello.
你好。
I think it's the third day of the Webster Festival.
我想这是韦伯斯特节的第三天。
So today we have the, you know, every year the Webster Festival is going to have the
所以今天我们有，你知道，每年韦伯斯特节都会有
East Day each year.
每年东日。
So today is the third day, and we will the whole day discussing about the Ethereum, which
那么今天是第三天，我们将一整天讨论以太坊，
is the truly innovation came from.
才是真正的创新而来。
And I think Aya, it's your first time to be in Hong Kong, we are really happy to, really
我想阿雅，这是你第一次来香港，我们真的很高兴，真的
glad to have you here.
很高兴你来到这里。
Because I think for this year, there are lots of the audience from the broader ecosystem.
因为我认为今年有很多观众来自更广泛的生态系统。
And maybe some of them may be familiar with Ethereum, but some of them may not.
也许他们中的一些人可能熟悉以太坊，但有些人可能不熟悉。
And maybe you could introduce more about yourself and how is the Ethereum foundation's role
也许您可以更多地介绍一下您自己以及以太坊基金会的作用
in the ecosystem.
在生态系统中。
Do my own introduction?
我自己介绍一下吗？
Okay.
好的。
Hi.
你好。
Hello, everyone.
大家好。
My name is Aya Miyaguchi.
我的名字是宫口绫。
I am from the Ethereum Foundation.
我来自以太坊基金会。
I've been with the Ethereum Foundation since, officially since 2018, but before that, maybe
我从 2018 年起正式加入以太坊基金会，但在那之前，也许
I can just share a little bit of myself, is that I joined the industry 2013.
我可以简单分享一下我自己的情况，我是2013年加入这个行业的。
I was like, early founding members of the Kraken Exchange, if you have heard of it.
我当时想，Kraken 交易所的早期创始成员，如果你听说过的话。
But anyway, the reason why I joined the industry, that was a very early time still.
但无论如何，我加入这个行业的原因还是很早的。
And I thought this technology, blockchain technology can, back then, this was before
而且我觉得这个技术,区块链技术可以,当时,这是以前
Ethereum time.
以太坊时间。
So the Bitcoin, I thought it would be revolutionary for improving financial inclusion in the industry.
因此，我认为比特币对于改善该行业的金融包容性将是革命性的。
So that was my original interest.
这就是我最初的兴趣。
And then I ended up joining Ethereum, the world of Ethereum.
然后我最终加入了以太坊，以太坊的世界。
I did meet Vitalik and the team when Ethereum was about to start.
当以太坊即将启动时，我确实见到了 Vitalik 和他的团队。
My motivation to join the EF is this group of Ethereum is trying to maintain the properties
我加入 EF 的动机是这群以太坊正在努力维护属性
of blockchain, that blockchain promise to do purely, but also in a more broader way
区块链承诺纯粹但也以更广泛的方式做事
than what Bitcoin was able to do.
比比特币能够做的事情还要多。
So that mission itself was something that motivated me to participate and help.
所以这个使命本身就激励我参与和提供帮助。
And the Ethereum Foundation, what we do is actually support a lot of different activities
而以太坊基金会，我们所做的实际上是支持很多不同的活动
in the ecosystem, including protocols, development and research.
生态系统中，包括协议、开发和研究。
But Ethereum is a decentralized system that we do not own.
但以太坊是一个我们不拥有的去中心化系统。
That's a very important statement, and everyone should know.
这是一个非常重要的声明，每个人都应该知道。
So at this point, you don't need to trust EF for Ethereum to be...
所以在这一点上，你不需要相信 EF 以太坊......
It's been up and running for a decade with no downtime.
它已正常运行十年，从未出现过停机情况。
So we call ourselves one gardener of this big garden.
所以我们称自己为这个大花园的园丁。
So we try to support the ecosystem wherever the support is still needed.
因此，我们会尽力在仍然需要支持的地方支持生态系统。
If it doesn't need our help, that's great.
如果它不需要我们的帮助，那就太好了。
So that's...
所以那就是...
Sorry, I don't know.
抱歉，我不知道。
It's a very high level.
这是一个非常高的水平。
Yeah, because I think a lot of people, because the traditional way is that the foundation
是的，因为我认为很多人，因为传统的方式是基础
or the organization to support everything or to control everything.
或支持一切或控制一切的组织。
But I think it's totally different in the blockchain ecosystem, which especially in
但我认为在区块链生态系统中这是完全不同的，尤其是在
the Ethereum ecosystem.
以太坊生态系统。
So what do you think of the positioning that maybe EF and the broader ecosystem could have?
那么您如何看待 EF 和更广泛的生态系统可能拥有的定位？
So recently, we actually published this EF mandate.
最近，我们实际上发布了这项 EF 指令。
It's a long 38 pages, so I don't know if anyone has actually was able to read it.
长达38页，不知道有没有人真正能读懂。
But the motivation is that, like I said, the Ethereum's original promise comes with properties
但动机是，就像我说的，以太坊最初的承诺带有属性
such as, like we call it clubs, like censorship, resistance, open source, security and privacy.
比如，就像我们所说的俱乐部，比如审查制度、抵抗、开源、安全和隐私。
And those are the properties that actually can achieve that original promise.
这些属性实际上可以实现最初的承诺。
And EF needs to be opinionated to protect those properties.
EF 需要坚持己见来保护这些财产。
That's like a base layer, foundations of the platform, right?
这就像基础层，平台的基础，对吧？
And then only on this platform, only when the platform is preserved those properties,
然后只有在这个平台上，只有当平台保留这些属性时，
and that's when real adoption can happen.
那时才能真正被采用。
So there's a little bit of misunderstanding that after we published that, like people
所以在我们发布之后存在一些误解，就像人们一样
thought, okay, EF is going to only focus on that protocol layer, and then we don't really
我想，好吧，EF 将只关注该协议层，然后我们就不再关注了
care about that option.
关心那个选项。
That's actually the opposite, is because we care about the real adoption.
实际上恰恰相反，因为我们关心的是真正的采用。
The real adoption only happens when businesses are able to trust the foundational layer to
只有当企业能够信任基础层时，真正的采用才会发生
be able to handle like a billion dollar and also decade long operations.
能够处理十亿美元和长达十年的运营。
So you don't want to build business on something that can actually stop working in five years,
所以你不想把业务建立在五年内就会停止运作的东西上，
or like we have to protect that layer first.
或者就像我们必须首先保护该层一样。
And then the real adoption can actually solution can be built, like Dr. Shaw was providing
然后真正的采用实际上可以构建解决方案，就像肖博士提供的那样
some examples.
一些例子。
And so the way we see it is first that is for most important for any businesses, any
因此，我们认为首先对于任何企业、任何企业来说都是最重要的
builders to be able to build real application, real solutions.
构建者能够构建真正的应用程序、真正的解决方案。
And then the rest is where is the gap, right?
那么剩下的就是差距在哪里，对吗？
And then this event and today's, your activity is the, congratulations, EAG to launch, is
然后这个活动和今天的活动是，恭喜，EAG 启动了，是
that when we want to help, sometimes you don't even need us, but we want to help support
当我们想要提供帮助时，有时您甚至不需要我们，但我们希望提供帮助和支持
or at least encourage people to participate in the type of activities that can actually
或者至少鼓励人们参与实际上可以
multiply the benefits of the work everyone is doing.
使每个人所做的工作的效益成倍增加。
So everyone has different expertise, some people have more expertise in security, and
所以每个人都有不同的专业知识，有些人在安全方面有更多的专业知识，而
then you can use that as a strength for your own project.
那么你就可以利用它作为你自己项目的优势。
But then those security, privacy, those properties still needed in the applications there, because
但那里的应用程序仍然需要那些安全性、隐私性和这些属性，因为
we see every day in the ecosystem or globally, even outside of crypto, lack of those properties
我们每天都看到生态系统或全球范围内，甚至在加密货币之外，都缺乏这些属性
are causing a lot of problems to the end users.
给最终用户带来了很多问题。
When end users are affected, that's when the business also get affected, right?
当最终用户受到影响时，业务也会受到影响，对吧？
So you do have to care about the end users and then protect their own asset, their own
所以你必须关心最终用户，然后保护他们自己的资产，他们自己的
information.
信息。
So we don't really see the separation between, okay, we protect this on the protocol layer,
所以我们并没有真正看到之间的分离，好吧，我们在协议层上保护它，
but also as a whole, as an ecosystem, everyone needs to care about those properties.
但作为一个整体，作为一个生态系统，每个人都需要关心这些属性。
And then the application would be actually useful to help solve problems.
然后该应用程序将真正有助于帮助解决问题。
And those are the applications that can actually succeed and last long.
这些是真正能够成功并持续很长时间的应用程序。
Everything needs to stick in your business idea, or whether it's a business or whether
一切都需要坚持你的商业理念，无论是商业还是商业
it's a public system.
这是一个公共系统。
Yeah.
是的。
I still remember that during about 2018, i.com, you mentioned about the Infinity Garden, which
我还记得大约在2018年的时候，i.com，你提到了无限花园，
is really inspired at that time, because I seen lots of the foundations just to move
当时真的很受启发，因为我看到很多地基只是为了移动
forward and to be very aggressive, but the Infinity Garden, it's more like the way establish
前进并且非常激进，但是无限花园，它更像是建立的方式
the fundamental things for the ecosystem, for the builders, and give the space for them.
生态系统、建设者的基本事物，并为他们提供空间。
And for the mandate, which is released for the last month, is I think just like the restatement
对于上个月发布的授权，我认为就像重述一样
of the Infinity Garden.
无限花园。
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
Why this is the time again that we release that kind of the mandate?
为什么我们又在这个时候发布这样的授权？
And what do you see if the ecosystem, that EF doesn't play a central position, a central
如果 EF 生态系统没有发挥中心地位，你会看到什么？
role, that how could we still support the whole ecosystem and the builders?
角色，我们如何仍然支持整个生态系统和建设者？
Yeah.
是的。
So maybe I can give for some people who don't really know, Infinite Garden is the reframing
所以也许我可以给一些不太了解的人，《无限花园》是重构
that I've been using to reflect and also describe the Ethereum ecosystem actually beyond.
我一直用它来反映和描述以太坊生态系统的实际情况。
We said that in the mandate, the Infinite Garden is actually bigger than Ethereum, is
我们在任务中说过，无限花园实际上比以太坊还要大，是
the reason why is that is.
原因就是这样。
So there is a word we want to see, and that's the word, like people have freedom, like people
所以有一个词我们想看到，就是这个词，像人一样有自由，像人一样
have control over their own asset and then on their own information, and then all the
控制自己的资产，然后控制自己的信息，然后所有的
businesses are running, preserving that, everyone's freedom.
企业正在运营，维护每个人的自由。
And then for that to happen, if there's like a one organization, if EF says Ethereum is
然后为了实现这一点，如果有一个组织，如果 EF 说以太坊是
ours and we control everything, and even if we hire the best developers, best researchers
我们的，我们控制一切，即使我们雇用最好的开发人员、最好的研究人员
inside EF, which was actually suggested when I joined EF as an ED, there was pressure or
在 EF 内部，这实际上是我作为 ED 加入 EF 时建议的，有压力或
advice that I received that, oh, you should hire the best developer, best researchers
我收到的建议是，哦，你应该聘请最好的开发人员、最好的研究人员
internally and then build everything on our own.
内部，然后自己构建一切。
That sounds short-term, a lot easier to manage or easier to coordinate, and then Ethereum
这听起来很短期，更容易管理或更容易协调，然后是以太坊
may be able to move quicker to make progress, but at the same time, the progress and the
也许能够更快地取得进步，但同时，进步和
level of innovation is very limited, because even if we are pretty small, but even if you're
创新水平非常有限，因为即使我们很小，但即使你
a big corporation side, it's still limited, because the more we try to hold inside that
对于大公司来说，它仍然是有限的，因为我们越是试图将其保留在里面
true innovation doesn't happen.
真正的创新不会发生。
So the idea is to, how do we invite everyone to participate?
所以我们的想法是，我们如何邀请每个人参与？
And that's how, it's open source, anyone can participate, open source and permissionless,
就是这样，它是开源的，任何人都可以参与，开源且无需许可，
anyone can participate at the platform layer, but also anyone can participate in the middle
平台层任何人都可以参与，中间层也任何人都可以参与
layer or business layer, and then that way, we're, as a whole, this is the only way for
层或业务层，然后这样，我们作为一个整体，这是唯一的方法
us as a human to win this game, so that's the image of infinite game, but it's a garden
我们作为人类要赢得这场游戏，所以这就是无限游戏的形象，但它是一个花园
because there's a natural organic growth, like for example, we don't really control,
因为这是一种自然的有机增长，例如，我们无法真正控制，
we didn't really know, like when you started Shanghai Wu, like we didn't really tell you
我们真的不知道，就像你创办上海吴时一样，就像我们没有真正告诉你一样
what to do, you came up, and that's where the strength is, and the beauty is that by
该做什么，你就上来，这就是力量所在，而美丽就在于通过
us letting the control, the size and the growth, it's way bigger and it can multiply, and so
我们让控制、大小和增长，它变得更大并且可以倍增，所以
this is not really us trying to do a nice thing, it is a strategy to, for as a whole,
这并不是我们真正想做一件好事，而是一种策略，作为一个整体，
it can become a lot bigger than what one organisation can own.
它可以变得比一个组织可以拥有的规模大得多。
Yeah, and also, I think nowadays is a time from the infrastructure for move forward to
是的，而且，我认为现在是从基础设施转向的时代
the application side, do you think why it's also the time that release the mandate at
应用端，你觉得为什么现在也是发布授权的时间呢？
this particular time?
这个特定的时间？
Yes, so you know, like when people who've been in the industry for a while, at the earlier
是的，所以你知道，就像那些已经在这个行业工作了一段时间的人一样，在早期
time, when the ecosystem is smaller, it was easy for us to be all on the same page, right?
当时，当生态系统较小时，我们很容易达成共识，对吧？
So we run DevCon every year, that's the only big event that Ethereum Foundation runs, and
所以我们每年都会举办 DevCon，这是以太坊基金会举办的唯一大型活动，并且
then the first DevCon, DevCon 0, they call it DevCon 0, it was very small, like a fit
然后是第一个DevCon，DevCon 0，他们称之为DevCon 0，它很小，就像一个合适的人
in this size in the Berlin office, and it was easy for everyone to agree on, yes, this
在柏林办公室的这个规模，每个人都很容易同意，是的，这个
is the property, this is the values that we want to preserve, but once this is becoming
是财产，这是我们想要保留的价值观，但是一旦这成为
bigger, it is, it's becoming bigger than one room, and now it's global, we have people
更大，确实，它变得比一个房间还要大，现在它是全球性的，我们有人
in all different time zones, speak all different languages, and so there are principles we
在不同的时区，讲不同的语言，所以我们有一些原则
have learned on the way, actually Ethereum has learned, also EF has learned on the way,
一路上学到了，其实以太坊也学到了，EF也一路上学到了，
that how do we, first of all, when I came up with this flaming of Infinite Garden, the
首先，当我想到《无限花园》的火焰时，我们该如何做？
reason why I thought that was needed, originally, to the people in the Ethereum Foundation was
我认为以太坊基金会的人们最初需要这样做的原因是
that I want Ethereum not to lose the best part of Ethereum, which was how this global
我希望以太坊不要失去以太坊最好的部分，这就是这个全球性的
communities collaborate, and then on all different layers, everyone can participate, you go to
社区协作，然后在所有不同的层面上，每个人都可以参与，你去
hackathon, you learn, you teach each other, and then how do we preserve that, so that
黑客马拉松，你学习，互相教导，然后我们如何保存它，以便
was my motivation, so in the same way, at the protocol layer, the trade-offs are becoming
是我的动机，所以同样地，在协议层，权衡正在变得
harder, because there is always motivation, how do we make the transaction quicker and
更难，因为总有动力，我们如何让交易更快、更顺利
cheaper, and then that motivation is not crazy idea, that sounds very reasonable, then the
更便宜，然后那个动机不是疯狂的想法，听起来很合理，然后
question is, do we achieve that by compromising security or compromising decentralisation,
问题是，我们是否通过损害安全或损害权力下放来实现这一目标，
and you need to make hard decisions, and then at this point, we recognise that it's actually
你需要做出艰难的决定，然后在这一点上，我们认识到这实际上是
important for us to state that very clearly, what comes first, right, these properties
对我们来说很重要的是要非常清楚地说明什么是最重要的，对吧，这些属性
and then we think about usability and all this, because if we forget this, at the end
然后我们考虑可用性和所有这些，因为如果我们忘记了这一点，最后
of the day, user won't get benefit, that means the business won't succeed, and the ecosystem
一天之内，用户得不到利益，就意味着业务不会成功，生态系统也不会成功
won't grow, so we just decided to be clear on the order of importance, and at least EF
不会增长，所以我们决定明确重要性顺序，至少 EF
is going to be very opinionated to preserve that, that's what Vitalik, myself, discussed
为了保留这一点，我会非常固执己见，这就是维塔利克本人所讨论的
at the end of last year, now is the time for us to make it more explicit, like let's describe
去年年底，现在是我们把它说得更明确的时候了，比如让我们描述一下
how we are thinking and how we are going to do this, this is still 38 pages paper, it's
我们如何思考以及我们将如何做到这一点，这仍然是 38 页的纸，它
long but it still doesn't really explain everything, but at least the fundamental principles
虽然很长，但仍然不能真正解释一切，但至少解释了基本原理
are there, and that includes what you mentioned about how EF operates, we have this principle
都在那里，包括你提到的EF如何运作，我们有这个原则
of subtraction, EF only rules, we come in only when EF is needed, right, we don't need
减法，只有 EF 规则，只有需要 EF 的时候我们才进来，对，我们不需要
to be there if we are not needed, so one example is what you're doing, is if Hong Kong communities
如果不需要我们，我们就在那里，所以一个例子就是你们正在做的事情，如果香港社区
or Shanghai community or like other, work with other global communities and then start
或上海社区或像其他社区一样，与其他全球社区合作，然后开始
supporting builders, you are connecting with investors and builders and businesses and
支持建筑商，您正在与投资者、建筑商和企业建立联系，
institutions, and we've been supporting part of that, but also it would be great if others
机构，我们一直支持其中的一部分，但如果其他人也能这样做，那就太好了
can join the support together, so that's where we see things and that's where we decided
可以一起支持，所以这就是我们看到的事情，这就是我们决定的地方
to explain, make it clear on the mandate.
解释，明确任务。
Yeah, I think since the industry grows a lot to the mainstream and a lot of the newcomers
是的，我认为由于这个行业已经发展成为主流并且有很多新来者
join the industry, but there is still some key principles that we need to keep on, yeah,
加入这个行业，但我们仍然需要坚持一些关键原则，是的，
and this is how our industry, we use blockchain, we use user to achieve that, not just to go
这就是我们行业的方式，我们使用区块链，我们使用用户来实现这一目标，而不仅仅是去
back to the web to have the centralized dive, something like that, yeah, but there is also
回到网络进行集中式潜水，类似的东西，是的，但也有
question about the builders, you can see that some people may think that, okay, EF will
关于构建者的问题，你可以看到有些人可能会认为，好吧，EF 会
not do everything and how could you achieve not be at the central party or at the center
什么事都不做，怎么能做到不在党中央、不在中央呢？
of the stage, but still could support the builders, because some maybe think of EF is
阶段，但仍然可以支持构建者，因为有些人可能认为 EF 是
so far away, yeah.
这么远，是的。
So one thing I didn't, sorry, explain with your previous question was that I can give
所以抱歉，我没有用你之前的问题解释的一件事是我可以给
you more concrete example, Ethereum Foundation used to build a wallet, and Ethereum Foundation
你更具体的例子，以太坊基金会用来构建钱包，而以太坊基金会
used to provide only client geth, and that's how Ethereum started, right, if you remember
过去只提供客户端 geth，这就是以太坊的开始，对吧，如果你还记得的话
that time, and then people's expectation naturally was like, oh, EF is building a wallet, right,
那个时候，然后人们的期待自然是，哦，EF正在做钱包，对吧，
and then no one was motivated to even think about, should I build a wallet, and then,
然后没有人有动力去思考，我是否应该建造一个钱包，然后，
and back then, that wallet actually was not great, I mean, okay, like I can't really,
那时，那个钱包实际上并不好，我的意思是，好吧，就像我真的不能一样，
I respect the team, they tried, there was very new building Ethereum wallet was the
我尊重这个团队，他们尝试过，有一个非常新的以太坊钱包是
first thing and the new thing, but still, because EF doesn't have all the expertise
第一件事和新事物，但仍然是因为 EF 不具备所有专业知识
of everything, like security, you have to care about security, you have to care about
一切事情，比如安全，你必须关心安全，你必须关心
usability, and then it wouldn't be great if there's a wallet market, like natural competitions
可用性，然后如果有钱包市场，就像自然竞争一样，那就不太好了
out there, and so that's the challenge of one company, one organization try to own everything,
这就是一家公司、一个组织试图拥有一切的挑战，
it sounds very effective in a way, but it's not, it's not as a whole, so that's, that's,
从某种程度上来说，这听起来非常有效，但事实并非如此，它不是一个整体，所以，那是，
and then, so when we think about our position in supporting the ecosystem is how do we not
然后，当我们考虑我们在支持生态系统方面的立场时，我们如何不
become a bottleneck for the ecosystem true growth, so it could be like this building
成为生态系统真正增长的瓶颈，所以它可能像这个建筑
wallet, now actually our team, privacy team built Kohaku SDK, and that's like a tool for
钱包，现在实际上我们的团队，隐私团队构建了Kohaku SDK，这就像一个工具
wallets to be able to build privacy in a privacy system, and that kind of work is still there's
钱包能够在隐私系统中建立隐私，这种工作仍然存在
a gap, so our team worked on it, if anyone knows, actually our team worked together with other
差距，所以我们的团队致力于解决这个问题，如果有人知道的话，实际上我们的团队与其他团队合作
community members too, that's always, we try to work together with other teams outside, because
社区成员也是如此，我们总是尝试与外面的其他团队合作，因为
then there is not too much reliance on the Ethereum foundation, we call it walk away test,
那么对于以太坊基础就没有太多的依赖，我们称之为走开测试，
walk away test for Ethereum, like if all core devs walk away tomorrow, if can system survive,
对以太坊进行离开测试，就像如果明天所有核心开发人员都离开，系统是否能够生存，
and then stay up and running, right, that's the walk away, all walk away tests we want to do,
然后保持正常运行，对吧，这就是我们想要做的所有测试，
but also it's the same as ecosystem, if Ethereum foundation walks away tomorrow, can ecosystem
但也和生态系统一样，如果以太坊基金会明天离开，生态系统还能吗？
still be thriving and surviving, and I'm not saying that the answer is yes today yet, but
仍然蓬勃发展和生存，我并不是说今天的答案是肯定的，但是
that's where we want, we need to be thinking about this, and whether thinking or not that's
这就是我们想要的，我们需要思考这一点，无论思考与否
important difference. Yeah, I still remember that there is a very sentence in the mandate that
重要的区别。是的，我还记得授权书里有一句话，
inspired me a lot, is that EF were the first Ethereum steroids, but today we are one of
给我很大启发的是 EF 是第一个以太坊类固醇，但今天我们是其中之一
many, yeah, I think EAG is inspired by it a lot, because EAG doesn't ask for approval from EF,
很多，是的，我认为EAG受到了很多启发，因为EAG不要求EF的批准，
but we are still standing out to, okay, we could do a lot of things together to bring the
但我们仍然坚持认为，好吧，我们可以一起做很多事情来实现
ecosystem, stakeholders together to support more towards for the applications, yeah, so from your
生态系统、利益相关者共同支持更多的应用程序，是的，所以从你的
perspective, what do you see that this kind of the organization, just like no matter EAG or used
从角度来看，你对这种组织有什么看法，就像无论是EAG还是二手的
to be EA or some other organizations, all the builders stand out, and what do we see them,
对于 EA 或者其他一些组织来说，所有的构建者都脱颖而出，我们看到他们什么，
and what is the relation between them? So, yes, like you said, it's great that something like
它们之间是什么关系？所以，是的，就像你说的，这样的事情很棒
EAG is happening without us much involved, we can probably support communicating about EAG,
EAG 的发生无需我们太多参与，我们可能可以支持有关 EAG 的沟通，
but the rest is you can take care of it, seems like that's great, and like you said,
但剩下的就是你可以处理它，看起来这很棒，就像你说的，
yes, we see ourselves as one of many now, excuse me, so that's why subtraction at EF is actually
是的，我们现在将自己视为众多中的一员，请原谅，所以这就是为什么 EF 的减法实际上是
addition to Ethereum as a whole, and then, so your work and activities is one great example,
除了以太坊作为一个整体之外，然后，你的工作和活动就是一个很好的例子，
and when we see what kind of activities, even if you don't need our own support, like we want to
当我们看到什么样的活动时，即使你不需要我们自己的支持，就像我们想要的那样
spread the word and then help promote, is that what type of projects and organizations like EAG
传播消息然后帮助推广，像EAG这样的项目和组织是什么类型的？
are doing the work that actually impact can multiply, so like I said, do you also hold the
正在做的工作实际上影响力可以成倍增加，所以就像我说的，你也持有
same principles like we do, like okay, you want to invite everyone, it's not about you, I'm in the
和我们一样的原则，好吧，你想邀请所有人，这与你无关，我在
center, I have to control everything, I have to be the one to make all the decisions, and then the
中心，我必须控制一切，我必须成为做出所有决定的人，然后
gloss is not really, we don't really expect the gloss to be great for that, from that type of
光泽度并不是真的，我们并不真正期望光泽度能对此有很大帮助，从那种类型来看
activities, so when we see teams, it can be grantees, or like other events, or these community
活动，所以当我们看到团队时，它可以是受资助者，或者像其他活动一样，或者这些社区
organizers, what we try to see is that similar principles we have, are you willing to let go
组织者，我们想看到的是，我们有相似的原则，你愿意放手吗？
of the control and then actually help the gloss to be, yeah, multiply from there, so when we give
的控制，然后实际上帮助光泽度，是的，从那里乘以，所以当我们给出
support financially or just communication support, I always want to support things that the impact
经济上的支持或只是沟通上的支持，我总是想支持那些有影响的事情
doesn't stop there, there will be second order impact and third order impact, that's, you've been
还不止于此，还会有二阶影响和三阶影响，也就是说，你已经
seeing this already probably, that's why you believe in doing this way, I hope, yeah, because,
可能已经看到了这一点，这就是为什么你相信这样做，我希望，是的，因为，
but also another thing I care about this local first approach, you said I came to Hong Kong for
还有一件事我很关心这种本地第一的方法，你说我来香港是为了
first time today, and then I cannot really even pretend that I know a lot about Hong Kong, so if
今天第一次，然后我真的不能假装我对香港了解很多，所以如果
someone asks, how do you run business in Hong Kong, what's the best way, my best answer should be,
有人问，你在香港怎么做生意，最好的办法是什么，我最好的回答应该是，
I don't know, but I know people who know, right, and then I connect, so that's why I believe in
我不知道，但我认识知道的人，对吧，然后我就建立了联系，所以这就是我相信的原因
local first approach, because locals, there is like a local thing that only locals know, and then,
本地第一方法，因为本地人，就像本地的东西只有本地人知道，然后，
so how do we have global activities such as EAG, but still actually leverage locals' knowledge,
那么我们如何开展 EAG 等全球活动，同时又真正利用当地人的知识，
and then leverage locals' talents, and so who are thinking hard about that, we do pay attention to
然后利用当地人的人才，所以谁正在认真思考这一点，我们确实关注
this, I do pay attention to this, yes, yeah, and because I think for towards the future of the
这个，我确实关注这个，是的，是的，因为我考虑到未来
applications, and there are lots of the application builders here, and I think for no matter the
应用程序，这里有很多应用程序构建者，我认为无论
Infinity Garden or the mandate, it's such a deep philosophy design to give more space for the
无限花园也好，委托也罢，都是如此深刻的哲学设计，给更多的空间
builders, for everyone, and they could stand out to, okay, I can do this kind of thing in the
建设者，为每个人，他们可以站出来，好吧，我可以在
ecosystem to support each other, and also to do my own business, something like that, yeah, so what
生态系统互相支持，也做我自己的生意，类似的事情，是的，那又怎样
do you want to see to them, that if everyone wants to stand out, okay, I could do this kind of thing
你想告诉他们，如果每个人都想脱颖而出，好吧，我可以做这种事情
to support the whole ecosystem, what is your, could you give some words for them? What is my
支持整个生态系统，你的是什么，你能为他们说几句话吗？我的是什么
advice to them, or anything you want to encourage everyone, yeah, okay, yes, so I think this
给他们的建议，或者任何你想鼓励大家的事情，是的，好的，是的，所以我认为这个
Thermal Foundation doesn't often, or maybe, I don't have a lot of opportunity to talk to like
热粉底不经常，或者说，我没有很多机会跟这样的人交谈
all the startups out there, or businesses, or funders, but I do think, like I said in the
所有的初创公司、企业或资助者，但我确实认为，就像我在
beginning, what we are seeing in the ecosystem, or global tensions with all these geopolitics
首先，我们在生态系统中看到的，或者所有这些地缘政治的全球紧张局势
situations, solution has to be real, right, and then, and then, so what is, so often there have
在这种情况下，解决方案必须是真实的、正确的，然后，然后，所以，经常有
been attempts and then experiments in the industry that can be like a very short-term, quick, making
在行业中进行了尝试和实验，这可能是一个非常短期、快速的过程
money type of businesses, and it might be tempting to go toward that, it was probably tempting to go
金钱类型的企业，这可能很诱人，可能很诱人
toward that way, but now we are seeing that is, you really need to think seriously about security,
朝那个方向发展，但现在我们看到，你确实需要认真考虑安全问题，
for example, right, and it's not just your business, it's actually what is being built.
例如，对吧，这不仅仅是你的事，它实际上是正在建造的东西。